[
    {
        "id": 0,
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "Which is the Smallest Country in the World?",
        "a": "Maldives",
        "b": "Monaco",
        "c": "Vatican City",
        "d": "Montenegro",
        "answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "id": 1,
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "What is the currency of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia?",
        "a": "Riyal",
        "b": "Dinaar",
        "c": "Dirham",
        "d": "Shekel",
        "answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "Which of these edible items is not the leaf of a plant?",
        "a": "Tea",
        "b": "Coffee",
        "c": "Spinach",
        "d": "Lettuce",
        "answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "Which sport is Pete Sampras associated with professionally?",
        "a": "Golf",
        "b": "Tennis",
        "c": "Hockey",
        "d": "Boxing",
        "answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "Which of these is not an Ape?",
        "a": "Gorilla",
        "b": "Chimpanzee",
        "c": "Orangutan",
        "d": "Monkey",
        "answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "What does the 'C' in VCR stand for?",
        "a": "Cassette",
        "b": "Compact",
        "c": "Cable",
        "d": "Cinema",
        "answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "Who was the first person to reach North Pole?",
        "a": "Robert Peary",
        "b": "Robert Cook",
        "c": "Charles Hillary",
        "d": "Johan Don",
        "answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "Who the First Prime Minister of Britain?",
        "a": "John Blunt",
        "b": "Henry Waterloo",
        "c": "George Bush",
        "d": "Robert Walpole",
        "answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "Which country won the First Football World Cup?",
        "a": "Brazil",
        "b": "Uruguay",
        "c": "Belgium",
        "d": "Argentina",
        "answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "difficulty": 4,
        "question": "Who was the first female cosmonaut in Space?",
        "a": "Peggy Whitson",
        "b": "Svetlana Savitskaya",
        "c": "Sally Ride",
        "d": "Velentina Tereshkova",
        "answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "Where is The Engadin Valley located?",
        "a": "Egypt",
        "b": "Portugal",
        "c": "Switzerland",
        "d": "Turkey",
        "answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "difficulty": 4,
        "question": "Which of these is not a Stock Market index?",
        "a": "Nikkei",
        "b": "Sensex",
        "c": "Dow Jones",
        "d": "GATT",
        "answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "difficulty": 4,
        "question": "Who was Prophet Muhammads' father?",
        "a": "Abu Bakr",
        "b": "Abdullah",
        "c": "Abu Talib",
        "d": "Abd al Muttalib",
        "answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "Which is the first letter of the Arabic alphabet?",
        "a": "Alfa",
        "b": "Alif",
        "c": "Olfa",
        "d": "Calif",
        "answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "On which day of the year do Christians observe the 'twelfth night'?",
        "a": "5th January",
        "b": "25th December",
        "c": "31st December",
        "d": "23rd June",
        "answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "What is the Japanese business philosophy of continuous improvement called?",
        "a": "Karaoke",
        "b": "Kaizen",
        "c": "Kamikaze",
        "d": "Kimono",
        "answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "difficulty": 4,
        "question": "Which Soviet leader is associated with the terms 'Glasnost' and 'Perestroika'?",
        "a": "Mikhail Gorbachev",
        "b": "Boris Yeltsin",
        "c": "Vladimir Putin",
        "d": "Yuri Andropov",
        "answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "Who is the only woman to have received two Nobel Prizes?",
        "a": "Marie Curie",
        "b": "Aung San Su Kyi",
        "c": "Mother Teresa",
        "d": "Pearl S Buck",
        "answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "difficulty": 5,
        "question": "The medical term hysterectomy refers to the removal of which organ?",
        "a": "Kidney",
        "b": "Liver",
        "c": "Lungs",
        "d": "Uterus",
        "answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "Which is the largest state in the United States?",
        "a": "Alaska",
        "b": "Alabama",
        "c": "California",
        "d": "Texas",
        "answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "What did John Logie Baird invent?",
        "a": "Microwave Oven",
        "b": "Fax Machine",
        "c": "Television",
        "d": "Photocopier",
        "answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "difficulty": 4,
        "question": "Which country rules the Falkland Islands in the Atlantic Ocean?",
        "a": "Argentina",
        "b": "UK",
        "c": "Germany",
        "d": "France",
        "answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "Which of these sports has never been featured at the Olympics?",
        "a": "Cricket",
        "b": "Tug of War",
        "c": "Polo",
        "d": "Bowls",
        "answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "difficulty": 4,
        "question": "Who invented the Oral Polio Vaccine (OPV)?",
        "a": "Ronald Ross",
        "b": "Louis Pasteur",
        "c": "Francis Crick",
        "d": "Albert Sabin",
        "answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "difficulty": 4,
        "question": "Which was the first country to make Christianity the official religion?",
        "a": "Italy",
        "b": "England",
        "c": "Greece",
        "d": "Armenia",
        "answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "difficulty": 5,
        "question": "Where was the worlds' first fingerprinting bureau established?",
        "a": "Calcutta",
        "b": "Paris",
        "c": "New York",
        "d": "London",
        "answer": "a"
    }
    
]